<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[My code … :) :)]]></title>
  <link href="http://Dineshs91.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://Dineshs91.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-07-09T01:47:08+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://Dineshs91.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[DINESH S]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Python]]></title>
    <link href="http://Dineshs91.github.io/blog/2013/07/05/python/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-05T23:59:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://Dineshs91.github.io/blog/2013/07/05/python</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Python is an awesome scripting language. If you start learning python then you can wave goodbye to braces. Python is all about indentation. Python code is very clear and easy to understand. There are two versions of python you can choose from python 2 and python 3. Python 3 is the latest one but python 2 is also receiving updates and most of them use python 2. Its your choice to start with python 2 or 3. Let&rsquo;s talk about python in detail in the next post.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[learning python]]></title>
    <link href="http://Dineshs91.github.io/blog/2013/07/05/learning-python/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-05T23:48:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://Dineshs91.github.io/blog/2013/07/05/learning-python</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There are a lot of ways to learn python</p>

<p>The first way is to learn from the python official website &lsquo;python.org&rsquo;. Check the documentation section for tutorials. These tutorials are great and is a very good starting  point. All the basic concepts are there with sample examples.And the great thing about python is you can run the code in the terminal itself without having to create a new file each time you want to test a code. Just type python in terminal and you have an interpreter. You can run all the commands there.</p>

<p>Next have a look at &lsquo;learnpythonthehardway&rsquo; site. It also provides some good tutorials.</p>

<p>After learning the basics check this site &ldquo;<a href="http://code.activestate.com/recipes/langs/python/">http://code.activestate.com/recipes/langs/python/</a>&rdquo;. It has great python programs. Learn from others code look what libraries they are using. The best to way learn programming is by looking at others code and learn.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[MOOC]]></title>
    <link href="http://Dineshs91.github.io/blog/2013/06/30/mooc/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-30T19:25:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://Dineshs91.github.io/blog/2013/06/30/mooc</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>MOOC (Massive Open Online Courses) are becoming quite popular these days due to its free and worldwide availability. Some of them are Coursera and edx. Among these coursera has a lot of courses from various universities. You can take any course and obtain a statement of accomplishment. During the course you are to attend quizzes and do projects every week which account for the total credit you obtain for the course. Courses in coursera are very useful and most of them are self contained meaning they don&rsquo;t have any prerequisites and no study material is required. You could either view the videos on the site or you can download them to the local system and watch later.</p>

<p>MOOC&rsquo;s are the future. Because everyone has the opportunity to quality education and that too free. The only requirement is a system with internet connectivity.</p>

<p>Students all over the world are using these websites. So the discussion forums are very active. Some courses have peer assessment which is great way to learn.</p>

<p>Note: MOOC are nowhere near to the courses offered in those universities and the certificates are just a statement of accomplishment. Coursera is trying to get accredition for some of its courses.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Feeling excited with my first post]]></title>
    <link href="http://Dineshs91.github.io/blog/2013/06/30/feeling-excited-with-my-first-post/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-30T18:42:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://Dineshs91.github.io/blog/2013/06/30/feeling-excited-with-my-first-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Feeling great having posted my first blog.
Wow getting this post online was really a tough job.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
